A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Administrative papers FA140
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Administrative papers
circa 1949-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
FA140
11.88 Cubic Feet 27 boxes.
27 boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids
FA914 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, General and Professional correspondence.
FA964 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Biographical and Personal material.
FA965 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Personal and Professional papers.
Arrangement
The Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk materials are arranged into 4 components:
Administrative papers (FA140)
General and Professional correspondence (FA914)
Biographical and Personal Material (FA964)
Personal and Professional papers (FA965)
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, manuscript notes, photographs, reprints, clippings, budgets, photographs.
This group of D.W. Bronk's papers consists primarily of administrative files kept during his tenure as president of The Rockefeller Institute/ University, 1953-1968. The largest files are: Board of Trustees, Buildings and Grounds, Convocations, and The Rockefeller Institute/University Press. Correspondence of special interest is noted in the right-hand column of the folder listing, and is also indexed by name of correspondent in the card file.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 303
Medical sciences; Biology -- Research; Physiology; Aviation medicine; Operations management; Medical research; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Unesco; National Science Foundation. (U.S.); National Research Council. (U.S.)
- Administrative papers, 1949-1975; 10 Cubic Feet
  - American College Public Relations Association (ACPRA), 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Circular letters, membership material.
  - Anniversary celebration, 50th Anniversary of the First Laboratory, 1954 October 15; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    Notes, News releases, printed material, responses to invitation.
  - Announcements of lectures, seminars and courses, 1964-1970; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
    Memoranda.
  - Announcements and Memoranda, Miscellaneous, 1954-1971; 3 folders (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Announcements and Memoranda, Miscellaneous, 1954-1971; 3 folders (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - "Appreciations", 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Correspondence.
  - Architects and architecture, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ART
    - "Lavoisier and his wife", Portrait by Jacques-Louis David (1788), 1955-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, Catalogues.
    - Portraits of T.M. Rivers and D.W. Bronk; artists: A. Jonniaux (TMR) and J.C. Johansen (DWB), 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Photo of TR portrait.
    - Purchases, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Arts and Crafts Exhibition, The Rockefeller Student and Faculty Club, 1967 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Exhibit catalogs.
    - Association of Graduate Schools in the Association of American Universities, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Transcript of DWB remarks and discussion.
    - Auditors, 1956-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BEQUESTS
    - Caspary, Alfred H. Estate, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Photo of Caspary House at De Bruce.
    - Cohn, Alfred E., 1957-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Correspondence, Notes, Clippings.
    - Fricke, Sophie D., 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Martin, James D., 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Winterberg, Rudolph ("Mr. Vendome"), 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, Wills.
    - Witier, Juliette, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Correspondence, Documents.
    - Miscellaneous gifts and bequests, 1954-1964; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Berlin, Theodore H. (estate) and Patricia, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, Documents, personal letters, clippings.
  - Board of Scientific Directors (not RI/RU Presidential file), 1946-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, Notes, 1951 report.
  - BOARD OF TRUSTEES
    - Committees
      - Ad Hoc Committee to Study the Financial Report of RIMR, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
        Correspondence, Minutes, financial data.
      - Ad Hoc Committee on Administrative Changes, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Audit Committee, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        Correspondence, Minutes.
      - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1956-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        Correspondence, Statistics, minutes, drawings, agenda, report.
      - Business Operations Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        Correspondence, Agendas, minutes.
      - Development Committee, 1960-1962 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Correspondence, Minutes, budget.
      - Development Committee (under President F. Seitz), 1971-1975; 3 folders (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
      - Educational Policies Committee, 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
        Minutes, reports.
      - Executive Committee, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Correspondence, Memoranda, ballots.
      - Gifts, Grants, and Bequests Comm., 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
        Correspondence, Notes, Memoranda, dinner arrangements.
      - Hospital Affairs Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        Reports.
      - Nomination of New Trustees Comm., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Presidential Selection Committee, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Correspondence, Notes.
      - Research Committee, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Retirement Committee, 1953-1956 1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        Minutes, memo, plan.
    - Individual Trustees
      - Baker, William O., 1960-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), News release, clippings.
      - Bard, Philip, 1955-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Correspondence, Reprint.
      - Bennett, George F., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Correspondence, Clipping.
      - Bronk, D.W., 1949-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Brownell, Kenneth and Elizabeth, 1954-1959 1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Dana, Richard H., 1956-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - David, Donald K., 1954-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Clippings, release.
      - Debevoise, Eli Whitney, 1954-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Correspondence, Clippings.
      - Debevoise, Thomas M., 1954-1959 1912 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        Correspondence, Memorial minute, 1912 memo, J.D. Greene to F.T. Gates on scientific achievements of RIMR.
      - Dilworth, J. Richardson, 1960-1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Dochez, A. Raymond ("Do"), 1955-1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - duVigneaud, Vincent ("Dee"), 1954-1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Gardner, John W., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        Correspondence, Clippings, release.
      - Handler, Philip, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        Correspondence, Release.
      - Harrison, Ross G. (re), 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 15)
        Correspondence, Biographical memoirs.
      - Henry, Barklie McKee ("Buz") and Margaret, 1954-1968; 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
        Correspondence, Memo, obits, proposal for professorship.
      - Kimball, Lindsley F., 1954-1975; 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
        Correspondence, Memos, releases, investment portfolio, printed matter.
      - Lockwood, John E. General, 1954-1974; 3 folders (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Lockwood, John E. General, 1954-1974; 3 folders (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
        - Law firm (Milbank, Tweed, Hope (& Hadley) bills, 1957-1967
          Bills.
      - Loeb, Robert F., 1954-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Murnane, George, 1955-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Correspondence, Clippings, 1969 memoriam.
      - Nickerson, Albert L., 1958-1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - O'Brien, Donal C. Jr., 1961-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Correspondence, Memoranda.
      - Rivers, Thomas R., 1955-1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Robbins, William J., 1956-1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        Correspondence, Reprint, blueprint. clippings.
      - Robinson, Edward, 1953-1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Rockefeller, David - General, 1953-1975; 4 folders (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
        Correspondence, Releases, clippings, printed matter.
        Conditions Governing Access note
        Closed.
      - Rockefeller, David - General, 1953-1975; 4 folders (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - President's Student Fund, 1965-1968
      - Rockefeller, John D. Jr., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Seitz, Frederick, 1962-1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Edric B., 1953-1960 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        Correspondence, Docket, memorial minute.
      - Traphagen, John C., 1954-1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Whipple, George H., 1954-1972; 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
      - Miscellaneous Trustee correspondence and notes, 1954-1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        Notes, Photos (Prints), Photo of architectural drawing Memorial Hospital expansion, blueprint, DWB notes for farewell. to trustees, ca. Oct 1968.
      - Trustee Newsletter, 1962-1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        Correspondence, Mss, Photos (Prints).
  - BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS
    - Avery Memorial Gateway, 1959-1967; 3 folders (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
      Correspondence, Drawings; includes letter from H.A. Schneider 22 Sep 1965 describing staff meeting at which Avery described nucleic acid work.
    - Avery Memorial Gateway, 1959-1967; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bells, 1962-1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Re suitable bell for RU to honor DWB's father. Photos of European church bells; Drawing of proposed memorial chapel.
    - Building program, 62nd-63rd St, 1939-1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Photos (Prints), Photos of construction and development, 1903-1941, 63rd-64th St. & East River; memos, reports, documents.
    - Buildings
      - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Hall and Dining Room, 1956-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        Memoranda, Miscellaneous.
      - Caspary Hall and Auditorium, 1955-1966; 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Notes, Lantern slides of architectural line drawings; Memoranda, DWB notes on occasion of 1st faculty lecture, blueprints, reports.
      - Founder's Hall, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Gasser Building, 1965; 2 folders (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
        Correspondence, Vibration analysis, blueprints.
      - President's House, 1954-1969; 4 folders (Box 9, Folder 4-7)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Memoranda, expenditures, blueprints.
      - Sophie Fricke Hall, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Room requests, dedication material.
      - (South Laboratory and Student Residence, 1954-1968; 2 folders (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
        Memoranda, blueprints, contracts.
      - Theobald Smith Hall, 1955-1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Memoranda, blueprint.
      - Tower Building, 1965-1968; 4 folders (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Blueprints, estimates, specifications, contracts, brochure. Photos. include DWB watching construction; color views of campus during construction B&W aerial views, model and drawing.
      - Miscellaneous re buildings, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        Mss, re lettering for Flexner, Smith, and Founder's Hall with blueprints); cornerstones for Caspary.
      - Children's Gardens, 1955-1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
        Correspondence, Budget.
      - Director's Office, 1935-1968; 5 folders (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
        Memoranda, blueprints, building statistics.
      - Director's Office, 1935-1968; 5 folders (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      - Landscaping, 1955-1971; 3 folders (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Drawings; photos of view N and S along York Ave., 1960.
      - Park: area (63rd-64th St), 1956-1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Parking, 1955-1968 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        Memoranda, drawings.
      - Trustees Committee, 1955-1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
        Photos (Prints), Memoranda, financial reports, list of buildings constructed between 1955 and 1968; photos of architect's drawings of Flexner Hall Circle, 1955.
      - Waterfront Property (61st-68th St.) (re heliport construction), 1923-1940 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - York Avenue Redevelopment, 1953-1967; 2 folders (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
        Correspondence, Memorandum, survey and analysis report, protest letters.
      - Business Manager (Flinn, Waldo), 1954-1965; 5 folders (Box 12, Folder 4-8)
        Memoranda, proposals, budgets; Includes 1931-32 vacation scheduled.
      - Business Manager, Assistant (Elliot, Roger C.), 1956-1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        Memoranda, budgets.
      - Campbell, Editha C., 1958-1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Campo, Anthony J., 1957-1970 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Printed reminiscences.
      - Charter
        - Amendments (to grant degrees, change name), 1954-1965; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
          Petition.
        - Booklet, 1950-1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
          Correspondence, Booklets and drafts.
      - Christmas (parties, cards, and letters), 1956-1974; 5 folders (Box 13, Folder 6-10)
        Correspondence, Notes, personal letters.
      - Christmas cards, Bronks, 1954-1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        Photos (Prints), photos of university.
      - Concerts Caspary Hall series, 1958-1968 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Correspondence, programs financial statements.
      - 1957 Musicale (Box 14, Folder 3)
        Notes, list of invitations.
      - Miscellaneous concerts, 1958-1961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        Correspondence, Programs, clipping.
      - Consolidated Edison Company, 1958-1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        Correspondence, Memoranda, clippings.
  - CONVOCATIONS
    - Honorary degrees, Giuseppe Gherado Forni, Thomas Sherrer Ross Boase, Baron Adrian, Jose Leon Barandiaran, Nabor Carillo, Nathan Marsh Pusey, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1959 May 21-22; 4 folders (Box 14, Folder 6-9)
      Correspondence, Notes, Photos (Prints).
    - Honorary degrees: Peyton Rous, Herbert S. Gasser, 1959 June 18 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, Notes, Announcements, clippings.
    - Honorary degree: A. Newton Richards, 1960 June 10 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, Notes, Memoranda.
    - Honorary degrees L Sir Hugh S. Taylor, Thomas M. Rivers, 1961 June 12 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, Notes, News release, clippings.
    - Honorary degrees: Niels Bohr, A.V. Hill, 1962 June 5; 2 folders (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
      Correspondence, Photos (Prints), News release, clippings. Candid photos, including I.I. Rabi.
    - Honorary degrees: Henry Allen Moe, Alan Tower Waterman, 1963 June 12 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, Mss, Notes, Photos (Prints), News release.
    - Honorary degrees: James Bryant Conant, 1964 June 12 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Honorary degree: Lee A. DuBridge, 1965 June 9 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, Notes, News release.
    - Honorary degrees: Eugene L. Opie, Donald D. Van Slyke, 1966 June (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Honorary degree: Vannevar Bush, 1967 June 7 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Honorary degree: J. George Harrar, 1968 June 11 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, Notes, News release, clipping.
    - Cooper, Jane, 1964-1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Cresap, McCormick, and Paget (Management Engineers), 1953 1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, Reports.
    - Dining Halls, 1954-1965 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - East Side Association, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, Circular letters.
    - Ettinger Program for Creative Writing, 1963-1965; 3 folders (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
      Correspondence, Agendas, news releases, requests, applications.
  - FACULTY
    - Academic Council General, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Notes, Nomination letters agendas.
    - Graduate Study Brochure, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, Drafts of booklet.
    - Academic Senate, 1963-1968 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Notes, Meeting agendas, proposals.
    - Committees
      - Appointments and Promotions, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        Minutes.
      - Behavioral Sciences Advisory Committee, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
        Memoranda, minutes, drafts for report.
      - Computer Committee, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 3)
        Proposal, report.
      - Survey Committees (Biology, Biomedical Sciences, Logic, Mathematics and Philosophy, Chemical Sciences, Physical Sciences), 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
        Memoranda, minutes, drafts of reports.
      - Miscellaneous committees, 1961-1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Club, 1966-1968 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, Clippings re New Worker cartoons, purchase for.
    - Faculty Housing, 1959-1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - FELLOWSHIPS
    - Sophie Fricke Fellowship
      - French Academy of Sciences, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        Correspondence, Curriculum Vitae's.
      - Royal Danish Academy of Sciences and Letters, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Royal Society of London, 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Swedish Royal Academy of Science, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous applications, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous requests for support, 1959-1967 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous re fellowships, 1958-1964 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      Correspondence, Leaflets.
  - Foreign students, 1962-1966 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, Brochures, newsletters.
  - Grants awarded, 1958-1964 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Greetings (Formal letters from DWB as President of RI/RU and NAS), 1959-1965 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Hervey, John P., 1954-1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Government docs.
  - Horsfall, Frank L., 1955-1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Hotel Carlyle, 1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Ideas" ("This is for a new confidential file of ideas in which we might file away ideas until I do something about them or finally abandon them. They are merely note Nov. 1954), circa 1954 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Library, 1954-1967; 2 folders (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    Correspondence, Book lists, reports, blueprints, statistics.
  - Lupinek, Bernard, 1957-1970 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1955-1964 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Medical Library Center of New York, 1958-1964 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Milbank, Twee, Hope, & Hadley, 1962-1967 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, bills.
  - Mirsky, Alfred and Sonia Wohl, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, News release, obituary.
  - Netherlands Universities Foundation for International Cooperation, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - New York Botanical Garden, 1955-1967 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, Brochure.
  - New York Center for Biomathematical Research, 1957-1961 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, Proposal, planning papers.
  - New York Hospital - Cornell Medical Center, 1957-1967 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Correspondence, Newsletters, clippings, memoranda.
  - New York State Society for Medical Research, 1951-1964 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Notes re RU History, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Notes, holograph and typescript.
  - O'Donnell, John J., 1962-1967 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Opie, Eugene L., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Memoranda, referee reports re Opie ms. on Chinese medicine.
  - Pedersen, O. Margery, 1956-1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Penndorf, Paul, 1956-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Personnel
    - Academic, Appointments, Promotions and Salaries, 1954-1963; 2 folders (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
      Correspondence, Tables.
    - General, 1957-1968 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Memoranda, wage schedules.
    - Insurance, 1957-1966 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous staff correspondence (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Arrangement note
      Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Petrzelka, Charles, 1955-1966 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, Budgets.
  - Population Council, 1954-1968 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Proposals and reports by the President concerning the development of the Rockefeller Institute", 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Summary listing.
  - Public Relations
    - General (Eugene H. Kone), 1956-1967 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Horizon article, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Correspondence, Mss, Ms. by H.S.F. Cooper, Jr.
  - Miscellaneous articles re RI/RU scientists, 1956-1968 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, Mss.
  - Receptions and Teas, 1956-1968 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, Printed matter.
  - Residence Halls, 1957-1964 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Lists of occupants.
  - "The Rockefeller Diet", 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, Reprint, clipping.
  - The Rockefeller Foundation Virus Laboratories, 1934 1954-1965 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Memoranda, staff lists, photos of lab (1965).
  - THE ROCKEFELLER INSTITUTE / UNIVERSITY PRESS
    - Editors
      - General (C.I. Campbell and W. Bayless), 1953-1975; 3 folders (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
      - Sutton, Joseph G., 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Other Presses
      - Cambridge University Press, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Columbia University Press, 1955-1961 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        Correspondence, Clippings, Xmas cards.
      - Oxford University Press, 1958-1963 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Publications
      - Annual Reports, 1955-1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
        Drafts.
      - Descriptive Pamphlet, 1956-1959 (Box 21, Folder 5)
        Correspondence, Notes, Drafts.
      - History of the Rockefeller Institute, George W. Corner, 1965, 1953-1966 (Box 21, Folder 6)
        Correspondence, Photos (Prints), Reviews.
      - Journals
        - Biophysical Journal, 1959-1967 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Journal of Biophysical and Biochemical Cytology/Journal of Cell Biology, 1953-1965; 2 folders (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
          Correspondence, Reports, statistics.
        - Journal of Clinical Investigation, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 10)
          Correspondence, Agreement.
        - Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1959-1967 (Box 21, Folder 11)
          Correspondence, Statistics.
        - Journal of General Physiology, 1954-1968 (Box 22, Folder 1)
          Correspondence, Mss, Ms: "Outline of the History of JPG" by Osterhout" 1 p 1955. Letter from George Wald to DWB 27 July 1966.
        - Journal of Lipid Research, 1963-1968 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        - Rockefeller Institute Quarterly/ RI Review/RU Review, 1957-1968; 2 folders (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
          Correspondence, Mss, Notes, Galleys.
        - Viewbook, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Seal, 1958-1965 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Sigma Xi, 1964-1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, Circulars.
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - State University of New York, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - STUDENTS
    - Orientation presentation, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Notes.
    - Personal correspondence (Box 22, Folder 11)